Register of the Jacques Leprette papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ministère des Affaires Étrangères File, 1946-2000
  - Ambassadeur, United Nations
    - Conferences, meetings, and official visits file
      - Visit of Andrew Young, Paris, France, 1979 June 28 (Box-folder 89: 13)
      - Visit of Bernard Dufourcq, New York City, 1979 July 2 (Box-folder 89: 14)
      - Visit of Louis de Guiringaud, New York City, 1979 September 10-16 (Box-folder 90: 1)
      - Visit of Jacques Leprette, Lebanon, 1980 March 17-20 (Box-folder 90: 2)
      - Visit of Jacques Leprette, Texas and New Mexico, 1980 April 16-22 (Box-folder 90: 3)
      - Meetings between Jacques Leprette and Jean FranÇpois-Poncet, New York City(?), 1980 May 31 - June 1 (Box-folder 90: 4)
      - Visit of Serge Maffert, New York City, 1980 June 9-13 (Box-folder 90: 5)
      - Visit of Jean FranÇois-Poncet, New York City, 1980 August (Box-folder 90: 6)
      - Meeting between Jacques Leprette and Edmund Muskie, 1980 September (Box-folder 90: 7)
      - Visit of Jean François-Poncet, New York City, 1981 February 27 - March 1 (Box-folder 90: 8)
      - Meeting of French permanent representatives to international organizations, Paris, France, 1981 March 9-11 (Box-folder 90: 9)
      - Visit of Kurt Waldheim, Paris, France, 1981 July 2 (Box-folder 90: 10)
      - Meeting between Claude Cheysson and Andrei Gromyko, New York City, 1981 September 25 (Box-folder 90: 11)
      - Visit of FranÇois Mitterrand, Yorktown, Virginia, 1981 October 17-19 (Box-folder 90: 12)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - Invitations and thank you letters, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 90: 13)
        - Letters of congratulation, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 90: 14)
        - Letters of welcome, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 91: 1)
      - A (Box-folder 91: 2)
      - B (Box-folder 91: 3-4)
      - C (Box-folder 91: 5)
      - D (Box-folder 91: 6-7)
      - E (Box-folder 91: 8)
      - F (Box-folder 91: 9)
      - G (Box-folder 91: 10)
      - H-I (Box-folder 92: 1)
      - J (Box-folder 92: 2)
      - K (Box-folder 92: 3)
      - L (Box-folder 92: 4-5)
      - M (Box-folder 92: 6)
      - N (Box-folder 92: 7)
      - O (Box-folder 92: 8)
      - P (Box-folder 92: 9)
      - R (Box-folder 92: 10)
      - S (Box-folder 92: 11)
      - T (Box-folder 92: 12)
      - U (Box-folder 92: 13)
      - V (Box-folder 92: 14)
      - W (Box-folder 92: 15)
    - Credentials, 1976 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - Interviews, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - Memoranda
      - 1976 (Box-folder 93: 3)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 93: 4)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 93: 5)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 93: 6)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 93: 7)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 93: 8)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 93: 9)
    - Notes, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 93: 10)
    - Press releases, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 93: 11)
    - Reports
      - "France et les Nations Unies,", 1978 (Box-folder 93: 12)
      - End of mission report, 1982 (Box-folder 94: 1-2)
    - Speeches
      - By Jacques Leprette
        - "New Issues and New Ways at the United Nations," New York City, 1977 April 13 (Box-folder 94: 3)
        - "La France et les Nations Unies," Colony Club, New York City, 1979 October 25 (Box-folder 94: 4)
        - Speech on Namibia, International Peace Academy, New Paltz, New York, 1979 November 18 (Box-folder 94: 5)
          Notes, program, and background materials
      - By others
        - Raymond Barre, 1977 September 15 (Box-folder 94: 6)
        - Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, 1978 May 25 (Box-folder 94: 7)
        - Louis de Guiringaud, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 94: 8)
    - Subject file, 1977-1980
      Clippings, correspondence, newswire reports, and pamphlet
      - Abu Daoud affair, 1977 (Box-folder 94: 9)
      - France--Economic conditions, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 94: 10)
      - John Paul II, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 94: 11)
    - United Nations sessions file
      Cables, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and speeches
      - General Assembly, 1978
        - Disarmament (Box-folder 94: 12)
        - Human rights (Box-folder 94: 13)
        - Namibia (Box-folder 94: 14)
      - Security Council
        - 1976
          - General (Box-folder 94: 15)
          - Cyprus (Box-folder 94: 16)
          - South Africa (Box-folder 94: 17)
        - 1977
          - Benin (Box-folder 95: 1-2)
          - Botswana (Box-folder 95: 3)
          - Comoro Islands (Box-folder 95: 4)
          - Cyprus (Box-folder 95: 5)
          - Middle East (Box-folder 95: 6)
          - Mozambique (Box-folder 95: 7)
          - Namibia (Box-folder 95: 8)
          - South Africa (Box-folder 95: 9)
        - 1978
          - General (Box-folder 95: 10)
          - Angola (Box-folder 95: 11)
          - Chad (Box-folder 95: 12)
          - Cyprus (Box-folder 95: 13)
          - International Court of Justice (Box-folder 95: 14)
          - Lebanon (Box-folder 96: 1-2)
          - Namibia (Box-folder 96: 3)
          - Rhodesia (Box-folder 96: 4)
          - United Nations Emergency Force (Box-folder 96: 5)
        - 1979
          - Angola (Box-folder 96: 6)
          - Central African Republic (Box-folder 96: 7)
        - 1980
          - Iran-Iraq War (Box-folder 96: 8-9)
        - 1982
          - Iran-Iraq War (Box-folder 96: 10)
          - Lebanon (Box-folder 96: 11-12)
  - Ambassadeur, European Community, 1982-1985
    - Administrative file
      - Entertainment, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 97: 1)
      - Equipment and vehicles, 1983 (Box-folder 97: 2)
      - Financial records, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 97: 3)
      - Guest book, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 97: 4)
      - Personnel
        - 1981 (Box-folder 97: 5)
        - 1982 (Box-folder 97: 6)
        - 1983 (Box-folder 97: 7-8)
        - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 98: 1)
      - Schedules of appointments and meetings, 1984
        - January-February (Box-folder 98: 2)
        - March-April (Box-folder 98: 3)
        - May-June (Box-folder 98: 4)
    - Briefing papers, 1981 (Box-folder 98: 5-7)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1985
      - A (Box-folder 99: 1)
      - B (Box-folder 99: 2)
      - C (Box-folder 99: 3)
      - D (Box-folder 99: 4)
      - E (Box-folder 99: 5)
      - F (Box-folder 99: 6)
      - G (Box-folder 99: 7)
      - H (Box-folder 99: 8)
      - I (Box-folder 99: 9)
      - J (Box-folder 99: 10)
      - K (Box-folder 99: 11)
      - L (Box-folder 99: 12)
      - M (Box-folder 99: 13)
      - N (Box-folder 99: 14)
      - O (Box-folder 99: 15)
      - P (Box-folder 99: 16)
      - R (Box-folder 99: 17)
      - S (Box-folder 99: 18)
      - T (Box-folder 99: 19)
      - V (Box-folder 99: 20)
      - W (Box-folder 99: 21)
    - European Community presidency file, 1983-1984
      - Preparatory materials
        - General, 1983
          - March-September (Box-folder 99: 22)
          - October (Box-folder 99: 23)
          - November (Box-folder 99: 24)
          - November (Box-folder 100: 1)
          - December (Box-folder 100: 2)
        - Dossier made for Jacques Leprette, 1984 (Box-folder 100: 3-4)
      - Executive records, 1984
        - January (Box-folder 100: 5)
        - February (Box-folder 100: 6-7)
        - March (Box-folder 101: 1-2)
        - April (Box-folder 101: 3)
        - May (Box-folder 101: 4-5)
        - June (Box-folder 101: 6-7)
    - Meetings and official visits file
      - Permanent Representatives Committee, Brussels, Belgium, 1982 March 25 (Box-folder 101: 8)
      - European Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1982 March 29-30 (Box-folder 101: 9-10)
      - Permanent Representatives Committee, Brussels, Belgium, 1982 May 15 (Box-folder 101: 11)
      - European Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1982 June 28-29 (Box-folder 101: 12)
      - Research Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1982 June 30 (Box-folder 102: 1)
      - European Council, Copenhagen, Denmark, 1982 December 3-4 (Box-folder 102: 2)
      - European Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1983 March 21-22 (Box-folder 102: 3)
      - European Council, Stuttgart, West Germany, 1983 June 17-19 (Box-folder 102: 4-5)
      - Visit of European Community ambassadors, France and Italy, 1983 September 26-29 (Box-folder 102: 6)
      - Special Council, Athens, Greece, 1983 November 9-11 (Box-folder 102: 7)
      - European Council, Athens, Greece, 1983 December 4-6 (Box-folder 102: 8-9)
      - Council of Ministers, Brussels, Belgium, 1984 January 23-24 (Box-folder 102: 10)
      - European Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1984 March 19-20 (Box-folder 102: 11)
      - European Council, Brussels, Belgium, 1984 March 19-20 (Box-folder 103: 1-4)
      - European Council, Fontainebleau, France, 1984 June 25-26 (Box-folder 103: 5-8)
      - European Council, Fontainebleau, France, 1984 June 25-26 (Box-folder 104: 1)
      - Visit of European Community ambassadors, Alsace, France, 1984 June 30 - July 1 (Box-folder 104: 2)
      - Economic and Financial Affairs Council, 1984 October 1 (Box-folder 104: 3)
      - European Council, Dublin, Ireland, 1984 December 3-4 (Box-folder 104: 4)
    - Memoranda
      - 1982 (Box-folder 104: 5)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 104: 6)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 104: 7)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 104: 8)
    - Notes
      - 1981 (Box-folder 104: 9)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 104: 10)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 105: 1-2)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 105: 3-7)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 105: 8)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 106: 1-2)
    - Printed matter
      - Bulletins, 1985 (Box-folder 106: 3)
      - Clippings, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 106: 4-5)
      - Monograph excerpt, 1971 (Box-folder 106: 6)
      - Pamphlets and serial issues, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 106: 7)
    - Reports
      - By Jacques Leprette, 1985 (Box-folder 106: 8)
      - By others, 1983 (Box-folder 106: 9)
    - Speeches
      - Raymond Barre, 1980 (Box-folder 106: 10)
      - Roland Dumas, 1985 (Box-folder 106: 11)
    - Subject file
      - Gibraltar--Politics and government, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 106: 12)
  - Ambassadeur de France
    - Appointments and assignments file
      - United Nations Management and Decision-making Project
        - Agendas and programs, 1986 (Box-folder 107: 1)
        - Clippings, 1985 (Box-folder 107: 2)
        - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 107: 3)
        - Papers and reports, 1986 (Box-folder 107: 4)
        - Summary of meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 107: 5)
      - Secrétariat General de la Défense Nationale
        - Clippings, 1987 (Box-folder 107: 6)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 107: 7)
        - Printed matter, 1987-1990
          - Brochure, 1987 (Box-folder 107: 8)
          - Monographs
            - 1989 (Box-folder 107: 9)
            - 1990 (Box-folder 107: 10)
        - Records of study group meetings
          Agendas, correspondence, memoranda, and reports
          - 1988
            - October 14 (Box-folder 107: 11)
            - November 18 (Box-folder 107: 12)
          - 1989
            - January 6 (Box-folder 107: 13)
            - April 28 (Box-folder 107: 14)
        - Report by Leprette, undated (Box-folder 108: 1)
        - Speeches, 1987 (Box-folder 108: 2)
      - Commission Nationale Consultative des Droits de l'Homme, 1987-1998
        - Correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 108: 3)
        - Records of meetings
          - 1987 (Box-folder 108: 4)
          - 1989 (Box-folder 108: 5)
          - 1991 (Box-folder 108: 6)
          - 1995 (Box-folder 108: 7-8)
          - 1996 (Box-folder 108: 9-12)
          - 1997 (Box-folder 109: 1-4)
          - 1998 (Box-folder 109: 5-6)
        - Reports, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 109: 7)
      - Commission des Archives Diplomatiques
        - Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 109: 8)
        - Printed matter, 1993-1994
          - Brochures, 1993 (Box-folder 109: 9)
          - Serial issue, 1994 (Box-folder 109: 10)
        - Records of meetings, 1992-2000
          - 1992 (Box-folder 109: 11)
          - 1993 (Box-folder 109: 12)
          - 1995 (Box-folder 110: 1)
          - 1996 (Box-folder 110: 2)
          - 1998 (Box-folder 110: 3)
          - 1999 (Box-folder 110: 4)
          - 2000 (Box-folder 110: 5)
        - Reports, 1995-1999
          - 1995 (Box-folder 110: 6)
          - 1996 (Box-folder 110: 7)
          - 1997 (Box-folder 110: 8)
          - 1999 (Box-folder 110: 9)
      - Promotion of the French language and cooperation among Francophone populations
        - Correspondence, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 110: 10)
        - Memoranda, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 111: 1)
        - Printed matter
          - Clippings, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 111: 2)
          - Bulletin and guide, 1993 (Box-folder 111: 3)
          - Serial issues, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 111: 4-5)
        - Reports
          - By Leprette, 1996 (Box-folder 111: 6)
          - By others, 1996 (Box-folder 111: 7)
        - Speeches, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 111: 8)
    - Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 111: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1996
      - A (Box-folder 111: 10)
      - B (Box-folder 111: 11)
      - C (Box-folder 111: 12)
      - D (Box-folder 111: 13)
      - E (Box-folder 111: 14)
      - F (Box-folder 112: 1)
      - G (Box-folder 112: 2)
      - H (Box-folder 112: 3)
      - I (Box-folder 112: 4)
      - J (Box-folder 112: 5)
      - K (Box-folder 112: 6)
      - L (Box-folder 112: 7)
      - M (Box-folder 112: 8)
      - N (Box-folder 112: 9)
      - P (Box-folder 112: 10)
      - R (Box-folder 112: 11)
      - S (Box-folder 112: 12)
      - T (Box-folder 112: 13)
      - U (Box-folder 112: 14)
      - V (Box-folder 112: 15)
      - W (Box-folder 112: 16)
    - Memoranda
      - 1985 (Box-folder 112: 17)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 112: 18)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 112: 19)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 112: 20)
    - Personnel files
      - Abraham, Ponnou, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 112: 21)
      - Fino, Albert, 1985 (Box-folder 112: 22)
      - Gosson de Varennes, Alexis, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 112: 23)
      - Pellet, Alain, 1988 (Box-folder 112: 24)
      - Vanderhagen, Édouard, 1986 (Box-folder 112: 25)
  - Représentant de la France, United Nations Commission on Human Rights, 1987-1991
    - Cables, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 113: 1)
    - Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 113: 2)
    - Commission on Human Rights sessions file, 1988-1991
      Agendas, correspondence, memoranda, notes, and reports
      - 1988 (Box-folder 113: 3-4)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 113: 5-6)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 113: 7)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 113: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 113: 9)
    - Meetings and official visits file, 1988-1990
      - Visit of Edwige Avice, Geneva, Switzerland, 1988 September 1-2 (Box-folder 113: 10)
      - Commemoration of the 40th anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, Paris, France, 1988 December 10 (Box-folder 113: 11-14)
      - Meeting of French officials with non-governmental organizations, Paris, France, 1989 January 23 (Box-folder 114: 1)
      - Visit of Jean Pierre-Bloch, Geneva, Switzerland, 1989 March 9 (Box-folder 114: 2)
      - Colloquium on the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child, Versailles, France, 1989 November 24 (Box-folder 114: 3-4)
      - Meeting of French officials with non-governmental organizations, 1990 January 22 (Box-folder 114: 5)
    - Memoranda
      - 1987 (Box-folder 114: 6)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 114: 7-8)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 114: 9)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 114: 10)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 114: 11)
    - Notes, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 114: 12)
    - Reports
      - By Leprette
        - 1988 (Box-folder 114: 13)
        - 1988 (Box-folder 115: 1)
        - 1989 (Box-folder 115: 2)
      - By others
        - 1987 (Box-folder 115: 3)
        - 1988 (Box-folder 115: 4-5)
        - 1989 (Box-folder 115: 6)
- Directeur, Service de Liaison Interministériel pour L'Information File, 1959-1968
  Administrative file, clippings, correspondence and memoranda, notes, and subject file, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Administrative file
    - Budgets, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 115: 7)
    - Equipment and supplies, 1964 (Box-folder 115: 8)
    - Mission and tasks, 1964 (Box-folder 115: 9)
    - Offices, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 116: 1)
    - Organization, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 116: 2)
    - Personnel, 1964 (Box-folder 116: 3)
    - Radio and television committees, 1965 (Box-folder 116: 4)
  - Clippings, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 116: 5)
  - Correspondence and memoranda
    - General
      - 1963 (Box-folder 116: 6)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 116: 7)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 116: 8)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 116: 9)
    - Peyrefitte, Alain
      - 1963 (Box-folder 116: 10)
      - 1964
        - January-June (Box-folder 116: 11)
        - July-December (Box-folder 116: 12)
      - 1965
        - January-June (Box-folder 116: 13)
        - July-December (Box-folder 116: 14)
    - Vaurs, Roger
      - 1963 (Box-folder 117: 1)
      - 1964
        - January-March (Box-folder 117: 2)
        - April-June (Box-folder 117: 3)
        - July-September (Box-folder 117: 4)
        - October-December (Box-folder 117: 5)
      - 1965
        - January-March (Box-folder 117: 6)
        - April-June (Box-folder 117: 7)
        - July-December (Box-folder 117: 8)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 117: 9)
  - Notes
    - 1964
      - January-June (Box-folder 118: 1)
      - July-December (Box-folder 118: 2)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 118: 3)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 118: 4)
  - Presidential campaign file
    Correspondence, memoranda, notes, printed matter, and reports
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - 1965
        - January-June (Box-folder 118: 5)
        - July-December (Box-folder 118: 6)
    - Printed matter
      - Brochures and pamphlets, 1965 (Box-folder 118: 7)
      - Leaflets, 1965 (Box-folder 118: 8)
      - Monograph, undated (Box-folder 118: 9)
      - Poster, undated (Box-folder 118: 10)
      - Serial issues, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 1)
    - Subject file
      - Films, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 2)
      - Opposition candidates, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 119: 3)
      - Press coverage, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 4)
      - Public opinion, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 119: 5)
      - Publications, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 6)
      - Radio and television broadcasts, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 7)
      - Speeches, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 8)
  - Reports
    - By Leprette, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 9)
    - By others, 1965 (Box-folder 119: 10)
  - Summaries of meetings
    - General
      - 1965
        - March-August (Box-folder 120: 1)
        - September-October (Box-folder 120: 2)
        - November-December (Box-folder 120: 3)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 120: 4)
    - Comités interministériels
      - 1964
        - January (Box-folder 120: 5)
        - February (Box-folder 120: 6)
        - March (Box-folder 120: 7)
        - April (Box-folder 120: 8)
        - May (Box-folder 120: 9)
        - June (Box-folder 120: 10)
        - July (Box-folder 120: 11)
        - September (Box-folder 120: 12)
        - November (Box-folder 121: 1)
    - Comités restreints
      - 1964
        - March (Box-folder 121: 3)
        - April (Box-folder 121: 4)
        - May (Box-folder 121: 5)
        - June (Box-folder 121: 6)
        - July (Box-folder 121: 7)
        - September (Box-folder 121: 8)
        - October (Box-folder 121: 9)
        - November (Box-folder 121: 10)
        - December (Box-folder 121: 11)
      - 1965
        - January (Box-folder 121: 12)
        - February (Box-folder 121: 13)
        - March (Box-folder 121: 14)
        - April (Box-folder 121: 15)
        - May (Box-folder 121: 16)
        - June (Box-folder 122: 1)
        - July (Box-folder 122: 2)
        - September (Box-folder 122: 3)
        - October (Box-folder 122: 4)
        - November (Box-folder 122: 5)
        - December (Box-folder 122: 6)
    - Meetings with Georges Pompidou
      - 1964 (Box-folder 122: 7)
      - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 122: 8)
- Conferences, Seminars, and Official Visits File, 1975-2003
  Brochures, correspondence, lists of participants, memoranda, papers, reports, transcripts of proceedings, and other materials, arranged chronologically by name of event and alphabetically by physical form thereunder
  - Bons offices et médiation: la pratique, les recherches seminar, Académie Mondiale pour la Paix, Menton, France, 1975 January 13-18 (Box-folder 122: 9)
    Brochure, correspondence, and program
  - Conférence Interuniversitaire d'Études et de Recherches sur les Nations Unies et les Institutions Spécialisées, Institut du Droit de la Paix et du Développement, Université de Nice, France, 1976 February 26-28
    - Brochure (Box-folder 122: 10)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, and notes (Box-folder 122: 11)
    - Programs (Box-folder 122: 12)
  - Opinions publiques et paix internationale conference, Académie de la Paix, Monte Carlo, Monaco, 1983 March 24-26
    - Brochures (Box-folder 122: 13)
    - Correspondence, list of participants, and program (Box-folder 122: 14)
    - Notes (Box-folder 122: 15)
    - Papers (Box-folder 122: 16)
  - Défense et sécurité de l'Europe conference, Académie de la Paix, Monte Carlo, Monaco, 1984 February 23-25
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 122: 17)
    - List of participants and program (Box-folder 122: 18)
    - Notes (Box-folder 122: 19)
  - Visit of European representatives, Centre National d'Études Spatiales, Kourou, Guyana, 1984 April 25-28
    - Brochures (Box-folder 123: 1)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 123: 2)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 123: 3)
  - Conférence des chefs d'état et de gouvernement des pays ayant en commun l'usage du français, Paris, France, 1986 February 17-19
    - Press dossier (Box-folder 123: 4)
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings (Box-folder 123: 5)
      - Serial issues (Box-folder 123: 6)
      - Reports (Box-folder 123: 7)
      - Speeches (Box-folder 123: 8)
      - Transcript of proceedings (Box-folder 123: 9)
    - Post-conference committee meetings materials (Box-folder 124: 1)
      Correspondence, report, and speech
  - L'Europe et l'espace conference, Académie de la Paix, Monte Carlo, Monaco, 1986 April 17-19
    - Background papers (Box-folder 124: 2)
    - List of participants and program (Box-folder 124: 3)
    - Notes (Box-folder 124: 4)
  - Le français dans les organisations internationales colloquium, Paris, France, 1987 June 28 - July 1
    - Papers (Box-folder 124: 5)
    - Reports (Box-folder 124: 6)
  - Deuxième Conférence des chefs d'état et de gouvernement des pays ayant en commun l'usage du français, Québec, Canada, 1987 September 2-4
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 124: 7)
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings (Box-folder 124: 8)
      - Serial issues (Box-folder 124: 9)
    - Proposal (Box-folder 124: 10)
    - Reports (Box-folder 124: 11)
    - Transcript of proceedings (Box-folder 125: 1)
    - Post-conference committee meetings file
      Correspondence, reports, and transcripts of proceedings
      - 1987 (Box-folder 125: 2)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 125: 3-5)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 125: 6-9)
  - L'Après Québec: quelle stratégie pour la francophonie? conference, Institut du Droit de la Paix et du Développement, Université de Nice, France, 1987 December 12 (Box-folder 125: 10)
    Correspondence and program
  - Information, désinformation et sécurité internationale conference, Académie de la Paix, Monte Carlo, Monaco, 1988 March 3-5
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 126: 1)
    - Notes (Box-folder 126: 2)
    - Programs (Box-folder 126: 3)
  - La diplomatie dans les organisations internationale et la négociation multilatérale seminar, Institut International d'Administration Publique, Paris, France, 1988 April 18 - June 6
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 126: 4)
    - Program and syllabus (Box-folder 126: 5)
  - Future Role of the United Nations in an Interdependent World roundtable, United Nations Institute for Training and Research, Moscow, USSR, 1988 September 5-9
    - Agendas, lists of participants, and schedules (Box-folder 126: 6)
    - Background papers (Box-folder 126: 7)